#### Contact

+923360005351 (Mobile) mhaseebullah92@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/haseeb-ullah (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Microsoft Office

C++

Matlab

### Languages

Urdu (Native or Bilingual)
English (Limited Working)
Punjabi (Limited Working)

#### Honors-Awards

Merit Laptop by Punjab Government in Youth Initiative Program 2012 Awarded 100% Scholarship for my whole tuition fee by National ICT R&D Fund

# Haseeb Ullah

Senior Software Engineer at 10Pearls

### Summary

Software Engineer

I am a full stack developer having almost 5 years of industry experience as a back-end and a front-end developer. I am well aware of working in a Scrum/Agile software development environment.

I have an expert level of JavaScript working experience with a knowledge of how JavaScript works under the hood. As a front-end developer I have worked in the latest JavaScript frameworks (i.e. AngularJS, Angular, React). I have also experience in designing responsive pages with HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3 and bootstrap framework.

As a back-end developer, I have worked in a variety of back-end languages and frameworks i.e. C# (.Net Core, .Net framework), Python (Flask), Node.js (ExpressJS). In a variety of projects, I have implemented different programming concepts (i.e. Multi-Threading, Authentication, Authorization, Logging, Exception Handling, File Handling) and different software architectures including Microservice.

I have also experience in working with relational databases (i.e MS SQL Server, MySQL), writing complex queries, views and store procedures as well as with non-relational databases (i.e NoSQL, MongoDB).

I am a quick learner and always open to learning/explore the latest tools and technologies.

### Experience

10Pearls

#### Senior Software Engineer

March 2021 - Present (11 months)

Islāmābād. Pakistan

#### Synergy-IT Pakistan

Software Engineer

February 2018 - March 2021 (3 years 2 months)

Islamabad

#### Responsibilities:

- Designing and development of Web-Based software solutions.
- Enhancement and bug fixation of existing modules.
- · Participation in all phases of SDLC.
- · Communicating and coordinating tasks with team and client.

#### Technologies used:

Angular, AngularJS, ReactJS, Javascript, TypeScript, C#, .Net WebApi, .Net Core WebApi, LINQ, SQL, Azure DevOps, Html, CSS, Bootstrap.

#### E-strats

Software Developer

March 2017 - February 2018 (1 year)

Islamabad

#### Responsibilities:

- Responsible for maintenance of existing modules and enhancement of new modules of the application.
- Optimization and bug fixation for the daily usage of the customer.
- · Learning and implementing new technical concepts.
- Communicating and coordinating tasks with team and client.

#### Technologies Used:

C#, ASP.NET MVC, LINQ, SQL, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, Telerik UI Tools, Html, CSS.

#### Celestia Software (Pvt) Ltd.

ASP.NET Intern

November 2016 - February 2017 (4 months)

Rawalpindi

#### Responsibilities:

- Design, implementation, testing and deployment of the web-based application as a full-stack developer.
- Coordinate with the Team Lead on current programming tasks.

• Continuously learn and improve skills.

Technologies Used:

C#, ASP.NET MVC, LINQ, SQL, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, Html, CSS, Bootstrap

## Education

University of Engineering and Technology, Taxila

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Engineering · (2011 - 2015)